Mark P. Koivula

Data Analyst / Developer

CONTACT

127 Shady Oak Drive Email: mkoivula6515@gmail.com
Dickson, TN 37055 Email: mkoivula6515@gmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/MarkKoivula

(615) 812-1737 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-koivula/

PROFILE

A highly motivated BI developer with experience in querying, interpreting, and analysis of data obtained from a variety of sources. Skilled in analytical processes and methods to meet both internal and external requirements. Experienced in preparing detailed visualizations and reports while managing complex data analysis responsibilities. Strong and effective communication skills essential in conveying analytic results. Committed to data accuracy consistent with the highest standards of quality control

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- SQL Server 2019
- PostgreSQL
- Power BI
- Tableau
- Python

- Excel
- Jupyter Notebooks
- Kanban Boards
- SSRS
- Visual Studio 2019

- Visual Studio 2019
- TFS
- Git / GitHub
- AGILE methodology

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYST | 08/2020 to Current

Nashville Software School - Nashville, TN

- Used statistical reasoning methods through tools such as Python, SQL, Tableau and Power BI to deliver actionable insights
- Gained experience in analytical workflows, including data extraction, transformation, and results presentation
- Developed ability to communicate analysis results through data visualizations, data storytelling and dashboards

PROJECTS

Brewery and Beer Review Analysis

 Created Tableau dashboard from brewery and beer data from 2020 for analysis of craft beer and brewery user reviews to explore which beers ranked best overall and trends in beer consumption by state

Indeed Data Analyst Opportunities Analysis

 Created interactive <u>Power BI dashboard</u> for analysis of data analyst job openings for comparison by industry, by user star ratings and to identify job locations by state. Created mapping visualization to easily identify locations of individual job descriptions

WORK EXPERIENCE

REPORT DEVELOPER | 04/2017 to 02/2020

Centauri Health Solutions - Brentwood, TN

- Lead developer for Blue Cross/Blue Shield client partnership delivering key HEDIS metrics for data analysis in support for NCQA reporting
- Development of complex SSRS reports used to support operational and executive analysis.
- Responsible for data architecture and data delivery within guidelines of NCQA HEDIS measure specifications
- Data management including SQL database administration, SQL query development, optimization, and SQL script performance tuning and monitoring

SENIOR BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE DEVELOPER | 12/2015 to 04/2017 **Compassus - Brentwood, TN**

- Lead developer for strategic partnership initiative with Optum Healthcare delivering key reporting metrics for strategic operational trend forecasting
- Responsible for database architecture, data delivery, file extracts, ETL development, and developing financial and clinical reports
- Data warehouse management including SQL database administration, SQL development
- SSRS reporting development, performance tuning and system analysis
- Administration of SharePoint site including collection management, configuring site collections, managing user rights, creating content types, site columns, and templates
- Developed ETL process for transformation of XML files utilizing SSIS and PowerShell scripting for CAHPS survey reporting

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER | 04/2007 to 12/2015

Fresenius Medical Care - Cool Springs, TN

- Team lead developer for staffing optimization tool for clinical operations saving an estimated \$700,000 per year in staffing costs
- Responsible for analysis, design, and development of new clinical and financial business. applications
- Designed and implementation of ETL packages using DTS and SSIS
- Administered SharePoint document management system, responsibilities including configuring site
 collections, managing user security, creating content types, site columns, and templates
- Monitored existing production systems, provided incident management services, resolved application support issues

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School, Nashville TN

Data Analytics Program, Certificate of Completion, Expected Graduation January 2021

Tennessee Technological University - Cookeville, TN

Bachelor of Science, Management Information Systems, May 1997

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD

Microsoft Certified Enterprise Applications Developer, December 2005